Sometime in the early 1960s, a significant thing happened in Sydney, Australia.
20世纪60年代初的某个时候，澳大利亚悉尼发生了一件意义重大的事。
The city discovered its harbor.
这座城市发现了自己的港湾。
Then, one after another, Sydney discovered lots of things that were just sort of there — broad parks, superb beaches, and a culturally diverse population.
接着，悉尼又接二连三地发现了许多似乎一直就在那儿的东西——宽阔的公园、绝佳的海滩，以及文化多元的居民。
But it is the harbor that makes the city.
但真正成就这座城市的，是它的港湾。
Andrew Reynolds, a cheerful fellow in his early 30s, pilots Sydney ferryboats for a living.
安德鲁·雷诺兹三十出头，是个乐呵呵的小伙子，以驾驶悉尼的渡轮为生。
I spent the whole morning shuttling back and forth across the harbor with him.
我跟着他在港湾两岸之间来回穿梭了一整个上午。
After our third run Andrew shut down the engine, and we went our separate ways — he for a lunch break, I to explore the city.
第三趟跑完后，安德鲁关掉了发动机，我们便各走各的——他去吃午饭、休息，我去游览这座城市。
“I’ll miss these old boats,” he said as we parted.
“我会怀念这些老船的，”分别时他说。
“How do you mean?”
“这话怎么讲？”
I asked.
我问道。
“Oh, they’re replacing them with catamarans.
“哦，他们要用双体船来替换这些老船了。
Catamarans are faster, but they’re not so elegant, and they’re not fun to pilot.
双体船速度更快，但没那么优雅，开起来也没意思。
But that’s progress, I guess.”
不过，我想这就是进步吧。”
Everywhere in Sydney these days, change and progress are the watchwords, and traditions are increasingly rare.
如今在悉尼，无论走到哪里，变革与进步都是人们的口号，传统则越来越少见了。
Shirley Fitzgerald, the city’s official historian, told me that in its rush to modernity in the 1970s, Sydney swept aside much of its past, including many of its finest buildings.
该市的官方历史学家雪莉·菲茨杰拉德告诉我，20世纪70年代，悉尼在急于实现现代化的过程中，抛弃了许多过去的东西，其中包括不少最精美的建筑。
“Sydney is confused about itself,” she said.
“悉尼对自己的定位很困惑，”她说。
“We can’t seem to make up our minds whether we want a modern city or a traditional one.
“我们似乎拿不定主意，到底想要一座现代城市还是一座传统城市。
It’s a conflict that we aren’t getting any better at resolving.”
这是一个矛盾，而我们解决它的能力丝毫没有长进。”
On the other hand, being young and old at the same time has its attractions.
另一方面，既年轻又古老，也自有其魅力。
I considered this when I met a thoughtful young businessman named Anthony.
在结识一位名叫安东尼、颇有思想的年轻商人时，我想到了这一点。
“Many people say that we lack culture in this country,” he told me.
“很多人说我们这个国家缺乏文化，”他对我说。
“What people forget is that the Italians, when they came to Australia, brought 2000 years of their culture, the Greeks some 3000 years, and the Chinese more still.
“人们忘记了，意大利人来到澳大利亚时，带来了他们2000年的文化，希腊人带来了大约3000年的文化，中国人带来的还要更多。
We’ve got a foundation built on ancient cultures but with the drive and dynamism of a young country.
我们的根基建立在古老文化之上，同时又有着一个年轻国家的干劲与活力。
It’s a pretty hard combination to beat.”
这样的组合，相当难以超越。”
He is right, but I can’t help wishing they would keep those old ferries.
他说得对，但我还是忍不住希望他们能保留那些老渡轮。